# 孙俪
Sun Li
# 别碰我 疼
Don't touch me. It hurts
# 你这块是什么
What's that on you?
# 是不是孙俪这儿也有一个这个啊
Does Sun Li also have it at the same position?
# 孙俪的在这
Sun Li has one here
# 是吗
Really?
# 疼死了
It hurts so much
# 在这跟大家说一下
Let me tell you guys
# 有痘的不要抠
If you have a pimple, don't scratch it
# 千万不能抠
Don't ever scratch it
# 所以你今天不能笑了
So you can't lauch today
# 我今天只能嘿嘿
Today, I can only Heh Heh
# 大家好
Hi everyone
# 我是盗月社杨树梢
I'm Yang Shushao of DaoYueShe
# 我是沐上
I'm Mu Shang
# 今天我们来吃一个北方的菜
Today we'll have a northern dish
# 这个北方的菜其实挺有代表性的
This northern dish is actually quite typical
# 吃的是酱肉
It has Jiangrou (meat stewed with sauces)
# 炒合菜
Stir-fried Hecai (mixed stir fries)
# 春饼
Chunbing (wraps)
# 这个店很多人都来过
Many people have visitied the restaurant
# 老白也来吃过
Lao Bai have been here already
# 嗯
Hmm
# 这个菜主要是吃起来就扎实
Their good is so filling
# 特别适合中午的时候吃
Very good as lunch
# 马上开锅了
Cooking is about to finish
# 我们今天赶上第一锅
We are having the first batch of today
# 争取点上第一个肘子
Let's try to order the first knuckle
# 走吧
Let's go
# 还没人呢现在
No other customers yet
# 一掀帘子
As soons as we open the curtain
# 就是那个酱肉香味出来了
The smell of the Jiangrou is coming out
# 不要蒜汁吧
Any garlic sauce?
# 蒜汁要不要
Garlic sauce?
# 蒜汁
Garlic sauce
# 必须要
Absolutely yes
# 而且有蒜瓣吗 叔
And is there garlic cloves, uncle?
# 有
Yes
# 我抢答了
I rushed
# 这个叔叔的表情
The uncle's facial expressions...
# 你们发现了吗
Did you notice that?
# 他不笑的时候
When he's not smiling
# 你看不到他脸上有任何的勾勾褶褶
You don't see any wrinkles on his face
# 但是他一笑
But as soon as he smiles
# 马上所有的表情纹都出来了
All the wrinkles come out at once
# 所以他是很爱笑的一个人
So he must be smiling a lot
# 让我看有点像游本昌老师
To me, he looks like Mr. You Benchang
# 就是济公
I mean, Ji Gong
# 笑起来有点那个感觉
They feel alike when he smiles
# 您是哪的人
Where are you from?
# 我是河南永城
I'm from Yongcheng, Henan
# 在北京22年了
I've been in Beijing for 22 years
# 北京22年了
22 years in Beijing
# 22年了
22 years
# 太快了
Time flies
# 来了吗 这是我们的吗
Is it coming? Is it ours?
# 我们的肘子
Our knuckle
# 我们先尝一口这肉吧
Let's taste the meat first
# 因为这肉我现在看着有点厚
Because the meat looks a bit thick
# 然后外面的皮看起来也挺厚
And the skin on the outside also looks pretty thick
# 我怕它会比较腻
Just in case if it feels greasy
# 我们现在把它划开看一眼
Now we pull it open and take a look
# 真爽
So good
# 看这大肘子
Look at the big knuckle
# 因为它皮确实虽然很糯了
The skin is already very mush
# 整个肉质
But the overall texture
# 但是它还是很有韧劲的
It's still quite al dente
# 必须要带着肉皮吃一口搭配着瘦肉
So we must eat the lean meat together with the skin
# 怎么说呢
How do I put it?
# 倍香
Multiplicatively delicious
# 我吃的是瘦肉比较多
I've had a lot of the lean meat
# 肉香在你嘴里面觉得很爽
It feels so good when the flavor of the meat is in the mouth
# 然后它这个瘦肉部分炖的非常
And the meat has been stewed to very...
# 非常的烂
Very soft
# 我觉得老人也可以吃
I think even elders can eat it
# 对
Yeah
# 刚刚看那奶奶自己坐过来
I just saw that grandma, who came here herself
# 点了一份肘子
and ordered a knuckle
# 接着吃下去之后
And when you eat it
# 是那种咸香口
It's the savory and aromatic flavor
# 是通过咸度
It's the saltiness
# 通过它的酱汤煨出来的那种咸香口
The savory and aromatic flavor from the Jiangtang (soup with sauces)
# 就很足
Very rich
# 树梢姐
Shushao Jie (Jie = honorific)
# Hello
Hello
# 待会和你合个影可以吗
Can I take a photo with you later?
# 可以可以
Yeah, yeah
# 你知道大叔说什么吗
Do you know what the uncle said?
# 说是什么啊
What?
# 他说树梢姐
He said "Shushao Jie"
# 不是
No
# 他是说姐
He said "Jie" (honorific for older ladies)
# 没有
No
# 我不是
I'm not
# 不是 我今天早上起来
No. When I woke up this morning
# 明也觉得我老了
Ming also thought I'm older
# 不要这么想
Stop thinking like that
# 阿姨
Auntie
# 大家一定要记住
Guys, keep in mind that
# 今天是你人生中最年轻的一天
Today is the day when you are the youngest in your lifetime
# 接下来要做的吃法
They way we're gonna eat it next
# 搭配炒合菜
Is with the Hecai (stir-fried combo)
# 卷菜里面的最具有代表性的
The most typical food to be wrapped
# 就是炒这个合菜
is this Hecai
# 上面是金黄金黄的鸡蛋
On the top, a golden yellow egg
# 下面的是炒的
At the bottom, there are stir-fried
# 豆芽
Bean sprouts
# 韭菜
Chive
# 粉丝
Mung bean noodles
# 大家看看这个样子了吧
Guys, now you know how it looks like
# 盖张鸡蛋饼在上面
It's covered by a fried egg on the top
# 这时候就会有人问了
Now people may ask
# 为什么这个鸡蛋不炒碎了在豆芽里啊
Why not scramble the egg and mix it in the bean sprouts?
# 你说为什么鸡蛋不炒碎了在豆芽里啊
You know, why not scramble the egg and mix it in the bean sprouts?
# 在北京有这样的一个说法
In Beijing, there's a saying
# 这个菜还叫合菜戴帽
This dish is also called Hecai Daimao (Hecai with a hat on)
# 这个北方的寓意里面也是金银满堂
In the north, it implies full of gold and silver in the house
# 穿金戴银
Wearing gold and silver
# 图个吉利
It implies fortune
# 口感酸
The mouthfeel is sour...
# 酸
Sour...
# 说错了啊
My bad
# 河北话范了
I burst out Hebei dialect
# 口感酸爽清脆
The mouthfeel is sour, refeshing and crunchy
# 酸shan（爽）
Sour and refeshing?
# 河南话呢
How about in Henan dialect?
# 酸爽清脆
(In dialect) Sour, refreshing and crunchy
# 你听听俺这
(In dialect) Listen to me
# 唉
Eh
# 我发现用方言介绍食物
I found that if you introduce food in a dialect
# 会觉得特别的好吃
It feels especially tasty
# 你看这合菜
(In dialect) Look at the Hecai
# 豆芽炒粉条
(In dialect) Stir-fried mung bean noodles with bean sprouts
# 加上那个韭菜
(In dialect) Together with the chives
# 小椒辣椒一爆香
(In dialect) With the chili peppers fried aromatic
# 酸爽清脆
(In dialect) Sour, refreshing and crunchy
# 是不是立刻觉得好吃了
Does it feel much more tasty?
# 比普通话觉得好吃多了
Much more tasty than standard Mandarin
# 有一种吃那个河南烩面的感觉
Feels like eating the Huimian noodles in Henan
# 有股烩面位味儿
Feels like Huimian noodles
# 卷饼吃吧
Do we wrap it and eat?
# 对
Yes
# 这个真的是卷春饼超好吃
This tastes really good if you wrap it in the Chunbing
# 老顾客其实都会这样吃
All the old customers eat like that
# 一张沉甸甸的春饼
One heavy piece of Chunbing
# 把它一分为二
Divide it into two
# 加一块肥肉皮
Add a fatty piece of skin
# 加上一点瘦肉
Add some lean meat
# 然后蘸一下蒜汁
And dip it in the garlic sauce
# 这个里边是浓浓的蒜末
There's thick garlic mince inside
# 上面飘着香油
With sesame oil floating on the top
# 来一块合菜
Some Hecai
# 鸡蛋要来一块
A piece of egg
# 这卷子就扎实了
Now the wrap is made firm
# 加了合菜之后呢
With Hecai added
# 这个饼的味道其实就多了一个层次
There's one extra layer of flavor in the wrap
# 因为刚刚你吃的纯肉的那种
Because you just had some pure meat, you know
# 香味
Fragrance
# 纯肉香
Fragrance of meat only
# 现在呢 它不仅在口感上给你做的那种
Now, not only the texture has become
# @#¥¥*&¥%
@#¥¥*&¥%
# 它在肉上面咕噜咕噜
It's meat plus gulugulu
# 它不是那种咕噜咕噜
And it's not just that kind of gulugulu
# 而是那种@#¥……
But instead the @#¥……
# 大佬你别掀桌子大佬
Bro, don't freak out bro
# 你们这么说观众哪听得懂
How is the audience supposed to understand?
# 那你说
How about you do it
# 你说
You do it
# 吃起来怎么样
How does it taste like?
# 吃起来啊
It tastes like...
# 太尴尬了我
I feel so cringy
# 太尴尬了
Too cringy
# 我以为他能说出什么惊世骇俗的话
I thought he could say something distinguishing
# 你们是盗月社是吗
Are you DaoYueShe?
# 是
Yes
# 唉 同学
Hey, bro
# 那你觉得吃起来怎么样
So what do you think it tastes like?
# 吃起来bia叽bia叽的
It tastes like biajibiaji
# bia叽bia叽的
Biajibiaji
# 确实如此
Absolutely
# 说的很准确吧
Very accurate, right?
# 比什么哐嘁哐嘁强多了
Much better than your kuangjikuangji
# 那是
Exactly
# @#¥%
@#¥%
# 吃这个啊一定要配蒜
This must be eaten with garlic
# 吃肘子的时候
When you eat pork knuckle
# 它流出来的汤汁啊
The juice the comes out
# 会比较黏
is a bit sticky
# 因为它这里面的胶质胶原蛋白会多一些
Because it contains more collagen
# 因为毕竟这么大块厚的猪皮在里面
Because there's a big piece of thick pork skin
# coco的降温方法总是这么的物理
The way coco cools down stuff is always so physical
# 机器过热
The machine is overheating
# 一会儿coco那手冻住了在那
In a while, coco's hand will freeze there
# 好
Alright
# 现在其实已经到了中午12点了吧
Now it's already 12 o'clock at noon
# 人慢慢已经很多了
More people have come
# 我们走吧
Let's go
# 拜拜
Bye bye